You must have seen the numbers of ICS Lombard this morning
and CFO
Gopal Bal Chandan has joined us to discuss these.
Sir, Namaskar, welcome to the program.
I would like to know exactly from
you a little about the details of these Q3 numbers
and especially how your market
share, the market share trend, direction has been
looking in the health and motor insurance space and what will be
its direction. The performance
of ICC Lombard, I think its outcome, if you have
seen that we have made a very good profit,
but not just profit, if you
also look at the growth in comparison to the industry,
on a nine-month basis, for example, the
industry's growth has been 7.8, while ICS
Lombard in nine months has been at about
10.3. So, as I had said earlier,
relative to the industry, the outperformance of ICC Lombard will be
approximately between 100 to 200 basis points
and if you look at the actual result also, within that
range.  So,
in general, it has been a very, very satisfying quarter. What
we have seen is our approach to
writing risk in terms of driving
profitable growth. So, we have been kind of sticking to that, and
since the outcome that you are seeing in terms
of top-line growth and
in terms of profit and combined ratio, the
whole thing is pretty much in line
with our expectations, but having said that, I think
for us, I think there is a lot
we can do, whether in terms
of growth or if you talk about
claims centers, I
think there is a lot that we can
obviously work on as an institution, and
our endeavor will be that we are able to kind of work
on all of those and continue
to deliver an outcome which will be
relatively
sustained profits over very long periods
of
time. Okay, Gopal ji, I come to what you just
mentioned, what you mentioned
about your combined ratio, because
accounting  If you look at the standards,
that meaning is visible in it, but exactly
where is that adjusted combine ratio
rotating, it is floating right now. What about the
insurance that we offer
to our customers, first of all, we
can say that many of our
insurance solutions are largely one year
risk coverage, but equally
in some product lines like health, like
home, like other retail lines, beyond that,
our insurance coverage can
also be for more than one year, like
in health, we provide three year coverage,
I understand your point, Gopal ji,
now let's come a little bit to the distribution
front. Now, Atley, from here,
how strong will your own distribution front be or more or less,
your dependence will depend on the bank channels,
how are
you strengthening the distribution network, from an ice low stand
point and this is not a matter of today, it is the way we have kind of
run the operations in general,
if you look at our  The distribution
breakup has been quite a lot of distributors
across various distribution
channels. If you talk about motor dealers, if
you talk about agents, if you talk about bank
distribution, which you were talking about, or
equally, our digital opportunity, then from a firm standpoint,
our investment has been
in all distribution channels, more or less, equally across
various time periods, and that's how we will
focus. So, that's our concentration
on a particular channel as much as possible. We have
tried to kind of keep that minimal.
And if you talk about banks, for us,
banks are very important distributors, but
if you look at the
access that customers have, customers can get their rent
requirements from dealers. A lot of customer
rent requirements can be fulfilled through agents.
Okay, Gopal ji, thank you very much for
joining this conversation, for us, we talked about it, and
you also gave a tip about the future. Thank you, and
best of luck to Nenwa Nibal Pul Bak Lo Karb.
Nifty IT with a pullback of 50 70 80 880 points is
today's leader and one stock to keep an eye on is
TS Reliance which is trying its best to give the required push to Nifty
and beat as well Bajaj Finance and Bajaj Fun
Server. However, on this program, we pause the trading for the day
and the next program is
Traders Hotline. If you have any question,
please ask. Next program on the platform of CNB Savas
with Kanchan and Sh.
Hello, we